<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Hi, I'm Nhân - posts</title><link href="https://hi.imnhan.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="/feeds/posts.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://hi.imnhan.com/</id><updated>2016-03-12T01:13:00+07:00</updated><subtitle>and this is my humble corner on the interwebs.</subtitle><entry><title>I did NOT sign that online petition!</title><link href="https://hi.imnhan.com/posts/i-did-not-sign-that-rmit-sc-petition/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-03-12T01:13:00+07:00</published><updated>2016-03-12T01:13:00+07:00</updated><author><name>Bùi Thành Nhân</name></author><id>tag:hi.imnhan.com,2016-03-12:/posts/i-did-not-sign-that-rmit-sc-petition/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This evening I received a rather strange&amp;nbsp;email:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/rmitsc_01_wtf.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Um&amp;#8230; I don&amp;#8217;t remember signing any petition recently (or ever, for that&amp;nbsp;matter)?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What&amp;nbsp;happened?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apparently someone used my &lt;span class="caps"&gt;RMIT&lt;/span&gt; student email address to sign some petition for disbanding the
university&amp;#8217;s Student Council. Said petition was apparently started by some …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This evening I received a rather strange&amp;nbsp;email:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/rmitsc_01_wtf.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Um&amp;#8230; I don&amp;#8217;t remember signing any petition recently (or ever, for that&amp;nbsp;matter)?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What&amp;nbsp;happened?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apparently someone used my &lt;span class="caps"&gt;RMIT&lt;/span&gt; student email address to sign some petition for disbanding the
university&amp;#8217;s Student Council. Said petition was apparently started by some Ms. Trần Ngọc Tuệ Mẫn -
Student Council&amp;#8217;s vice president. Well&amp;#8230; yay for free speech, I guess? Anyway, my name was really
among the signers&amp;nbsp;list:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/rmitsc_02_names.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How did this happen? Well, turns out &lt;strong&gt;iPetition does not require email confirmation upon
signing&lt;/strong&gt;, so anyone can effectively enter any email and name they want and the stupid website will
happily accept that as an absolutely definitely most positively legit supporter of your cause. Cool&amp;nbsp;huh?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Upon further inspection, almost all of the signer names are in one same format: the one that &lt;span class="caps"&gt;RMIT&lt;/span&gt;
uses for its student names. So apparently a very motivated supporter of Ms. Mẫn&amp;#8217;s&amp;#8230; interesting
campaign has been helpful enough to go through &lt;span class="caps"&gt;RMIT&lt;/span&gt; students&amp;#8217; IDs and names and sign us up, without
us even having to know what it&amp;#8217;s all about. Gee,&amp;nbsp;thanks!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Why do I even&amp;nbsp;care?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I just don&amp;#8217;t like people using my name without my consent. More importantly, I have my reasons to
disagree with the sentiments expressed in her petition description. Also I thought this could be a
somewhat useful public service announcement, or a mildly entertaining daily wtf story. I don&amp;#8217;t&amp;nbsp;know.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hell, let&amp;#8217;s throw in some of my own random thoughts to make this more like a blog&amp;nbsp;post:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What&amp;#8217;s with these petition websites? Have people actually achieved anything using these? Even if
  a petition website does send confirmation emails, what&amp;#8217;s stopping me from using trash addresses?
  The signers&amp;#8217; email addresses are not displayed anyway so president@rmit.edu.vn won&amp;#8217;t be too
  different from lol0042@spam.me now, will it? If you&amp;#8217;re an official co-leader of something
  official who wants to do something official about it, maybe try a more, I don&amp;#8217;t know, official&amp;nbsp;channel?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The number of signers keep going up steadily, but slowly. Maybe our friendly neighborhood
  signerman is doing it all by hand instead of a script? If it&amp;#8217;s the former&amp;#8230; let&amp;#8217;s say I do
  admire the dedication &lt;strike&gt;and abhor the absolute stupidity&lt;/strike&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is it normal for a student council to be this full of&amp;nbsp;drama?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That concludes my mostly pointless blog post. Hopefully I&amp;#8217;ll come up with something actually worth
sharing soon. Until then, have an awesome&amp;nbsp;weekend!&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="posts"></category></entry><entry><title>My first DIY fightstick - Part 2</title><link href="https://hi.imnhan.com/posts/my-first-diy-fightstick-part-2/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-01-23T17:10:00+07:00</published><updated>2016-01-23T17:10:00+07:00</updated><author><name>Bùi Thành Nhân</name></author><id>tag:hi.imnhan.com,2016-01-23:/posts/my-first-diy-fightstick-part-2/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s been a while since I &lt;a href="https://hi.imnhan.com/posts/my-first-diy-fightstick-part-1/"&gt;started&lt;/a&gt; my arcade stick project. To be honest I got lazy and paused
the whole thing for a while, but yesterday I needed a distraction so&amp;#8230; everything came together
much more nicely than I&amp;nbsp;thought!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;I did&amp;nbsp;it!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was almost done in …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s been a while since I &lt;a href="https://hi.imnhan.com/posts/my-first-diy-fightstick-part-1/"&gt;started&lt;/a&gt; my arcade stick project. To be honest I got lazy and paused
the whole thing for a while, but yesterday I needed a distraction so&amp;#8230; everything came together
much more nicely than I&amp;nbsp;thought!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;I did&amp;nbsp;it!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was almost done in Part 1, except for the fact that button holes on the top panels didn&amp;#8217;t align,
and the topmost panel flexed a bit because of imprecise screw&amp;nbsp;holes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Ewww" src="/images/fightstick_24_gap.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To fix the button holes, I simply wrapped my roughest sandpaper around the drill bit and used it as
a poor man&amp;#8217;s sander to make the holes slightly bigger, just enough for buttons to fit. This took a
while because the sandpaper pieces kept failing on me. Good thing I stock a huge roll in the first
place!&amp;nbsp;:-)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The flexing panel was surprisingly trivial to fix: I simply made one corner&amp;#8217;s hole a bit bigger to
allow its screw to go all the way in properly. No more stupid&amp;nbsp;gaps!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that every piece was how it should be, the fun part began: assembling. The inside looked like&amp;nbsp;this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/fightstick2_01_wires.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notice the knot where the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;USB&lt;/span&gt; cable poked out? It was there as a safeguard against pulling so that
the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;PCB&lt;/span&gt; doesn&amp;#8217;t get yanked around. Later on I actually labeled every pair of wires for each button
and secured the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;PCB&lt;/span&gt; better with more resilient tape, but I forgot to take photos and I&amp;#8217;m now too
lazy to open up the whole thing again so&amp;#8230; you get the&amp;nbsp;idea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for the top panel artwork, I planned quite a few colored designs, but was too lazy to go to a
printing shop. As luck would have it, I had a black and white printer at home, so I grabbed some
random Galford image on the internet and printed out one sheet just to see how it would look. It
turned out much better than expected so I kept it that&amp;nbsp;way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/fightstick2_02_top.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note that I bought translucent buttons. These are worth the higher price tag because it is possible
to take them apart and &lt;a href="http://forums.shoryuken.com/discussion/25926/guide-how-to-put-art-under-clear-seimitsu-buttons"&gt;insert artwork pieces&lt;/a&gt; under the cover. Just google custom fightsticks
and you&amp;#8217;ll find people making use of these buttons with &lt;a href="http://static.giantbomb.com/uploads/original/2/25628/2658140-photo+oct+04,+7+24+53+pm.jpg"&gt;stunning&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://technabob.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2011/09/custom-steampunk-fight-stick-by-sam-kurd-aka-b15sdm-designs.jpg"&gt;results&lt;/a&gt;. But then again,
I&amp;#8217;m a lazy butt so my minimalistic design actually saved me from some tedious button modding.
Maybe when I get better inspirations,&amp;nbsp;maybe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Following the monochrome theme, the placeholder &amp;#8220;Ken Flowchart&amp;#8221; bottom piece from last post became
official (I also trimmed the excess paper&amp;nbsp;later):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/fightstick_23_bottom.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh, and here&amp;#8217;s a front shot for completeness&amp;#8217;&amp;nbsp;sake:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/fightstick2_03_front.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Thoughts&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All in all, this turned out much better than I expected. The whole thing feels solid to play with,
and the plexiglass top panel makes a nice feeling palm rest. However, since I went a bit liberal on
panel layers, it&amp;#8217;s a tad heavier than my previous stick (which is already heavier than your average
big brand sticks). On the flip side, I can be more aggressive with my joystick spinning sessions
thanks to the extra&amp;nbsp;weight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m also thinking of adding non-slip padding to the bottom. I almost exclusively play with the
fightstick on my lap so it&amp;#8217;s not actually necessary gameplay-wise, but without padding, the bottom
screw heads stick out and would definitely scratch my table whenever I place the stick on it.
Better be safe than&amp;nbsp;sorry!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;#8217;s it! This project has been fun, and to me it served as an awesome gateway drug to the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;DIY&lt;/span&gt;
world. Hopefully I inspired some of you to start your own projects too. Let me know how it&amp;nbsp;goes!&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="posts"></category></entry><entry><title>My first DIY fightstick - Part 1</title><link href="https://hi.imnhan.com/posts/my-first-diy-fightstick-part-1/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-12-08T12:50:00+07:00</published><updated>2015-12-08T12:50:00+07:00</updated><author><name>Bùi Thành Nhân</name></author><id>tag:hi.imnhan.com,2015-12-08:/posts/my-first-diy-fightstick-part-1/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Ever since I started practicing Street Fighter seriously (albeit with modest results), I&amp;#8217;ve
always wanted to make myself a custom fightstick. Now that I&amp;#8217;m not working full-time for anyone,
there&amp;#8217;s no better time to Just Do&amp;nbsp;It.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;#8217;ve done any research on &lt;span class="caps"&gt;DIY&lt;/span&gt; fightsticks, you …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Ever since I started practicing Street Fighter seriously (albeit with modest results), I&amp;#8217;ve
always wanted to make myself a custom fightstick. Now that I&amp;#8217;m not working full-time for anyone,
there&amp;#8217;s no better time to Just Do&amp;nbsp;It.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;#8217;ve done any research on &lt;span class="caps"&gt;DIY&lt;/span&gt; fightsticks, you&amp;#8217;ll know that the 2 best places to find guides
are &lt;a href="http://www.slagcoin.com/"&gt;Slagcoin&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://forums.shoryuken.com/categories/tech-talk"&gt;Shoryuken Tech Talk&lt;/a&gt;. I decided to follow the &lt;a href="http://www.slagcoin.com/joystick/example2.html"&gt;basic
design&lt;/a&gt; on&amp;nbsp;Slagcoin:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://www.slagcoin.com/joystick/example2/simple1.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Materials and&amp;nbsp;tools&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you live in Hồ Chí Minh City like me, you can probably get everything you need from shops on
Bạch Đằng Street. The only hard part for me was convincing a small wood shop to sell &lt;span class="caps"&gt;MDF&lt;/span&gt; panels cut
to my specifications in small&amp;nbsp;quantity:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;4 pieces x 30cm x 20cm x 1cm&amp;nbsp;*&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 pieces x 20cm x 4cm x&amp;nbsp;2cm&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 pieces x 20cm x 7cm x&amp;nbsp;2cm&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 piece x 26cm x 4cm x&amp;nbsp;2cm&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;4 pieces x 34cm x 7cm x 2cm&amp;nbsp;*&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All that set me back 120,000 &lt;span class="caps"&gt;VND&lt;/span&gt;. The cost was mostly for cutting labor instead of actual material.
The items with asterisks (*) are those I bought in abundance to make room for drilling&amp;nbsp;errors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/fightstick_01_mdf.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The top panel would be layered with 1 &lt;span class="caps"&gt;MDF&lt;/span&gt; and 2 plexiglass pieces (mad illustrating skillz, I&amp;nbsp;know):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/fightstick_02_top_plan.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The bottom would simply be 1 &lt;span class="caps"&gt;MDF&lt;/span&gt; and 1 plexiglass so I could also insert bottom&amp;nbsp;artwork.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since I had zero woodworking experience, I joined the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;MDF&lt;/span&gt; pieces with simple butt joints and good
old wood glue. You&amp;#8217;ll notice that there&amp;#8217;s a significant gap on one corner - turns out the shop
wasn&amp;#8217;t too accurate with their cutting. It&amp;#8217;s not shown here but eventually I had to saw a longer
&lt;span class="caps"&gt;MDF&lt;/span&gt; piece to replace&amp;nbsp;it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/fightstick_03_glue.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I already had a hand drill laying around so all it took was buying a couple of hole saws - 24mm and
30mm in diameter respectively. The bigger one was used for drilling main button holes while the
other was for joystick hole and smaller front side&amp;nbsp;buttons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/fightstick_04_hole_saw.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Don&amp;#8217;t buy&lt;/strong&gt; hole saws like the one below - you will not be able to drill through thick panels
(like the 20mm thick one I&amp;nbsp;bought):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/fightstick_05_nope_saw.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for the actual parts, I ordered the joystick and buttons from &lt;a href="https://www.akishop.jp/"&gt;Akishop&lt;/a&gt;. It ships from
Japan so the shipping cost to Vietnam is much more reasonable than if I buy from the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;US&lt;/span&gt;. I also
bought a &lt;a href="http://www.ebay.com/itm/Zero-Delay-USB-Encoder-to-PC-Joystick-For-Arcade-DIY-KIT-Sanwa-Parts-MAME-/191558265304?hash=item2c99c329d8#shpCntId"&gt;Zero Delay &lt;span class="caps"&gt;PCB&lt;/span&gt; kit&lt;/a&gt; from ebay. This one even offers free shipping since it&amp;#8217;s from
China. This kit offers easy solder-free wires too so it saved me from a lot of trouble (I still
can&amp;#8217;t find where to quick-disconnect terminals to this date). I connected everything to my &lt;span class="caps"&gt;PC&lt;/span&gt; to
test if things worked as&amp;nbsp;expected:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/fightstick_26_electronics.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick note: the popular wisdom is to buy screw-in buttons for thick panels and scap-in for thin
ones. However, as my panel is &lt;em&gt;way&lt;/em&gt; too thick even for screw-ins, snap-ins are actually the better
choice: you just need to put the buttons in normally - the 2 sides of the button will push against
the hole and keep it there fairly firmly. I never had a problem with my previous stick which was
build this&amp;nbsp;way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Actually making&amp;nbsp;it&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I drilled holes in the front side: first using the 30mm bit to drill halfway, then went all the way
with the 24mm bit. This allows a small button to be placed deep into the case, avoiding
accidentally button&amp;nbsp;presses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/fightstick_06_front_holes.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then I glued the case body together. I didn&amp;#8217;t have big clamps laying around so I had to make do
with an elastic string. It worked terribly&amp;nbsp;though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/fightstick_07_glue_body.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note that the bottom panel was just there to keep the whole thing in shape. I took it out&amp;nbsp;later:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/fightstick_08_glue_body2.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See the gap in the top left corner? That&amp;#8217;s the gap I was talking about earlier. Good thing I had a
spare piece laying around, so I sawed it to the correct length to use as a&amp;nbsp;replacement:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/fightstick_09_saw_side.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now everything fitted together but there was some excess on one long side. Much sanding&amp;nbsp;awaits!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/fightstick_10_excess.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Initial sanding effort with 140 grit&amp;nbsp;sandpaper:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/fightstick_11_sanded.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the way, I recommend using a sanding block. It helps you apply more pressure evenly. I simply
wrapped my sandpaper around a spare piece of &lt;span class="caps"&gt;MDF&lt;/span&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/fightstick_12_sanding_block.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now on to the inner sides. These would support the top and bottom panels. I used a long piece of
scrap plexiglass to apply pressure instead of a clamp. This time I put one 10mm-thick wood panel
and one 3mm-thick plexiglass panel under it to make sure the inner supports are glued at the
correct&amp;nbsp;position.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/fightstick_13_inner_support.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With all 3 inner sides&amp;nbsp;glued:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/fightstick_14_inner_support2.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now you must be wondering why I had 2 inner pieces on the left side. I originally wanted to save
some space and weight by sawing those into shorter support bits instead of long whole pieces that
covered the full length. After sawing the first piece I decided that it wasn&amp;#8217;t worth the effort
anyway so&amp;#8230; there you have&amp;nbsp;it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here comes the next challenge: putting paint on the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;MDF&lt;/span&gt;. There is an &lt;a href="http://forums.shoryuken.com/discussion/67501/how-to-paint-mdf-to-a-mirror-finish-worklog"&gt;extremely elaborate
method&lt;/a&gt; explained on Shoryuken Tech Talk that helps you achieve a mirror-like glossy
finish. Of course I don&amp;#8217;t have the tools and patience to follow all that, but I followed the first
few steps (cover edges with non-absorbent material, sand and spray paint multiple times) to achieve
an acceptably smooth&amp;nbsp;finish.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;#8217;s the first step: cover edges with non-absorbent material. The tutorial suggested using
spackling, which I have no idea how to obtain from here. I settled with something Vietnamese people
&amp;#8220;matic&amp;#8221; (mastic, perhaps?) which my friends said was to be used for the same purpose. The thing was
yellow-ish and much more runny than spackling. It was also difficult as hell to work with: the
moment it&amp;#8217;s spread on the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;MDF&lt;/span&gt; edge, it starts drying, at which point you can&amp;#8217;t touch it again
unless you want an ugly grungy finish (is that even a&amp;nbsp;word?):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/fightstick_15_mastic.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I waited for the yellow thing to dry, then sanded it again. After a first few coats with glossy
black spray paint, things didn&amp;#8217;t look too&amp;nbsp;sexy:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/fightstick_16_first_coat.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It did get better with sanding (1200 grit) and more coats though. But then I made the most stupid
decision: glueing the top panel on before&amp;nbsp;drilling:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/fightstick_17_top_panel.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now why was this bad? Because now I would be forced to drill top panel holes &lt;em&gt;with&lt;/em&gt; the whole body
attached, which will expose the whole thing to sawdust, which was generally &lt;span class="caps"&gt;PITA&lt;/span&gt; to clean up - the
top panel made it a closed shape with corners and spaces all over the place. Also, if I screwed up
the top &lt;span class="caps"&gt;MDF&lt;/span&gt; panel (which I eventually kinda did), the whole thing would be&amp;nbsp;ruined.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As if that wasn&amp;#8217;t enough, I did paint it too. The paint layer would later make disgusting drill&amp;nbsp;holes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/fightstick_18_joystick_hole.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I&amp;#8217;m getting ahead of myself. Here&amp;#8217;s how the case looked after a few more black coats and one
clear coat (also put buttons in there to see how they&amp;nbsp;fit):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/fightstick_19_finished_coat.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did drill an extra button hole because I realized I&amp;#8217;d need the &amp;#8220;Playstation&amp;#8221; button too if I want
to use a &lt;span class="caps"&gt;PS4&lt;/span&gt; controller &lt;span class="caps"&gt;PCB&lt;/span&gt; later (which I plan to do). Unfortunately I only ordered 2 small
buttons from Akishop so I had to use a green Chinese button I had laying&amp;nbsp;around.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now here comes the hard part: drilling the top panel. As mentioned earlier, the top panel would be&amp;nbsp;3-layer:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/fightstick_02_top_plan.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I placed all 3 pieces onto the case, but with the 4mm plexiglass on top (in the plan it&amp;#8217;s supposed
to be in the middle - I&amp;#8217;ll explain later). Then I printed the Blast City button layout found on
Slagcoin and taped it onto the whole&amp;nbsp;thing:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/fightstick_20_top_layout.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notice the extra two holes I drew above and below the joystick hole. Those are for screw holes for
mounting the joystick. This is why I put the 4mm piece on top: I was going to drill these two holes
on the 4mm piece only to leave room for screw heads. This way I didn&amp;#8217;t need to &amp;#8220;route&amp;#8221; the extra 2
holes on my &lt;span class="caps"&gt;MDF&lt;/span&gt; piece like the original plan (I was afraid the 10mm &lt;span class="caps"&gt;MDF&lt;/span&gt; thickness was already too&amp;nbsp;thin).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After drilling the necessary holes, I removed the plexiglass pieces and drilled the aformentioned 2
joystick mounting holes into to &lt;span class="caps"&gt;MDF&lt;/span&gt;, then I placed the joystick mounting plate onto the surface to
plot the rectangular part that needed to be cut&amp;nbsp;off:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/fightstick_21_joystick_square.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since I don&amp;#8217;t have any power tool, I used my handy hand drill with the circular hole saw to
gradually drill out the&amp;nbsp;shape:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/fightstick_22_joystick_drills.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After much sanding and&amp;nbsp;cleaning:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/fightstick_18_joystick_hole.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See the glorious tears? That&amp;#8217;s what premature painting does to you. Friends don&amp;#8217;t let friends paint&amp;nbsp;prematurely!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, I also drilled 3 hole on the bottom to install the bottom pieces (1 &lt;span class="caps"&gt;MDF&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="amp"&gt;&amp;amp;&lt;/span&gt; 1 plexiglass). I
also printed a quick picture as a placeholder artwork to see how it would&amp;nbsp;look:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/fightstick_23_bottom.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I was excited to finish the putting the top panel together, I hit a wall: because I couldn&amp;#8217;t
possibly drill perfectly perpendicular screw holes, they could not property&amp;nbsp;attach:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/fightstick_25_loose_screw.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, thanks to the switching positions between the two plexiglass pieces, the button holes didn&amp;#8217;t
align anymore. I had to waste a buttload of time sanding the lower piece&amp;#8217;s holes to make them&amp;nbsp;bigger.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But that&amp;#8217;s not even the worst issue: because the screw holes were not aligned, once I screwed all
four corners, the top plexiglass piece flexed, creating a blatantly noticeable&amp;nbsp;gap:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/images/fightstick_24_gap.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Um&amp;#8230; that&amp;#8217;s it (for&amp;nbsp;now).&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;#8217;s all of my progress so far. I&amp;#8217;m visiting my &lt;a href="http://fablabsaigon.org/"&gt;local Fablab&lt;/a&gt;, which is advertised to
have &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CNC&lt;/span&gt; machines and laser cutters so I&amp;#8217;ll probably have a chance to produce more accurate panels.
Hell, I may even redo the whole thing using machine-cut pieces for absolute accuracy and save
myself from a world of&amp;nbsp;pain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I took a lot of photos as I went, so if you want to see more photos of my progress, just check out
my &lt;a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/nhanb/albums/72157661059385592"&gt;flickr album&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Till next&amp;nbsp;time!&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="posts"></category></entry><entry><title>Look ma, no stock theme!</title><link href="https://hi.imnhan.com/posts/look-ma-no-stock-theme/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-06-05T13:54:00+07:00</published><updated>2015-06-05T13:54:00+07:00</updated><author><name>Bùi Thành Nhân</name></author><id>tag:hi.imnhan.com,2015-06-05:/posts/look-ma-no-stock-theme/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2020 Update&lt;/strong&gt;: I bit the bullet and removed all web fonts, relying on the
browser&amp;#8217;s configured sans-serif/monospace fonts instead. It&amp;#8217;s probably fine,
since even stock fonts seem to cover Vietnamese glyphs well these days.
Otherwise, people who care enough to be bothered by fallback fonts are likely …&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2020 Update&lt;/strong&gt;: I bit the bullet and removed all web fonts, relying on the
browser&amp;#8217;s configured sans-serif/monospace fonts instead. It&amp;#8217;s probably fine,
since even stock fonts seem to cover Vietnamese glyphs well these days.
Otherwise, people who care enough to be bothered by fallback fonts are likely
to know how to configure their browser with proper fonts&amp;nbsp;anyway.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2017 Update&lt;/strong&gt;: Now that I like high contrast more, I just updated the theme to a
black/white/red palette with a [high-quality serif font][8] instead. Thanks [Mr.&amp;nbsp;Butterick][9]!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

I just redesigned my blog.

To be totally honest, the previous design was not mine at all. I&amp;#8217;ve always been using
[pelican-octopress-theme][1], which is a Pelican port of the default theme for Octopress. It&amp;#8217;s not
that I have anything to complain about that theme: it was clean, readable and easy on the eyes. I
just want my site to look unique. Content is king, sure, but it wouldn&amp;#8217;t hurt to stand out from the
crowd once in a while.

I&amp;#8217;m not a professional designer, but everything turned out quite well if I could say so. In this
post I&amp;#8217;ll explain my design goals and how I (hopefully) achieved them.

## Clean and lightweight

The web is messy. I&amp;#8217;m not talking blinking-marquee-fire-animated-header messy (thank god we&amp;#8217;re done
with that&amp;#8230; [or are we?][2]). I&amp;#8217;m talking megabytes-of-useless-javascript-and-css messy. For
whatever reason, some people now think it&amp;#8217;s cool to include Bootstrap/Foundation to every project,
or to include that new shiny parallax library to ruin scrolling for everybody. Oh, and don&amp;#8217;t forget
the marvellous invention that is [&amp;#8220;infinite scrolling&amp;#8221;][3]:

![](https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/infinite_scrolling.png)

In fact, the main motivation of my new theme is [this satire page][4] on the sad state of the web
we&amp;#8217;re in today.

That&amp;#8217;s why I decided to do no fancy cosmetic &lt;span class="caps"&gt;JS&lt;/span&gt; and try to keep my use of static assets to a
minimum:

![](/images/mofo_01_loads.png)

I guess there&amp;#8217;s nothing I can do about the font files though, since I need to make sure my
Vietnamese posts are rendered in a font that supports it. Oh well, at least it looks awesome.

## Content is king

No more distracting sidebar with &amp;#8220;latest news&amp;#8221;, &amp;#8220;related posts&amp;#8221;, etc. with thumbnails popping up
all over the place, just a good old article body from start to finish.

## Easy on the eye

While [bettermotherfuckingwebsite][5] does a good job at demonstrating how far you can go with a
few simple &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CSS&lt;/span&gt; rules (hint: very far), I found Tommi Kaikkonen&amp;#8217;s [Interactive Guide to Blog
Typography][6] much more comprehensive and informative. I implemented many of the ideas found
in that guide:

- Big body font
- Constrained line width to aid reading
- Generous line height, liberal whitespace to help with visual hierarchy
- Lower background-foreground contrast. I also find the slightly yellow-ish background somewhat
  soothing.

## That&amp;#8217;s it!

You can find the source code to my theme [on GitHub][7]. I don&amp;#8217;t recommend using it as-is though,
since I haven&amp;#8217;t implemented many required templates (authors, tags, categories, etc.) because I
don&amp;#8217;t use them. There&amp;#8217;s also the hardcoded content in footer and probably a few more places. Maybe
someday I&amp;#8217;ll stop being lazy and fix all that. *Maybe*.

[1]: https://github.com/duilio/pelican-octopress-theme/
[2]: https://developers.google.com/fonts/docs/getting_started#Effects
[3]: https://xkcd.com/1309/
[4]: http://motherfuckingwebsite.com/
[5]: http://bettermotherfuckingwebsite.com/
[6]: http://www.kaikkonendesign.fi/typography/
[7]: https://github.com/nhanb/motherfucking-pelican-theme
[8]: https://github.com/adobe-fonts/source-serif-pro
[9]:&amp;nbsp;https://practicaltypography.com/</content><category term="posts"></category></entry></feed>